that still works for the light because
were feels to me okay and one thing that
in the I was absolutely delighted to see
that extinction rebellion when they had
their first major action and London and
they were putting out the principles of
extinction rebellion which I think are
all very sound principles they they also
chose one which which is very close to
my heart having written a book called
designing regenerative cultures that was
called we need a regenerative culture
and then it even said the way described
what a regenerative culture is a culture
that is healthy resilient and adaptable
is a direct quote out of my book but the
difference what they did in quoting from
the book which I'm happy about about
that I did is they dropped the s they
dropped the plural of regenerative
cultures and said we need a regenerative
culture and then they started
communicating with all the networks that
are popping up around the world in that
way but really in each one of those
places that regenerative culture will
look slightly different so I think it's
really important to keep the plural
otherwise we have a form of
colonialization again we're a mainly UK
led initiative that spreads around the
globe is putting one particular form of
regenerative culture and they also sort
of collapsed it in two important things
the the culture care of within the
movement how do we support it other each
other how to support a culture of
communication that is this so people
don't burn out and they're people and
that there's less conflict all of this
is key to building a movement but
regenerative cultures is so much more
regenerative cultures is actually did
positive answer of saying we need an
extinction rebellion and therefore we
now need to join the regeneration and
build regenerative cultures everywhere
so so it's so for me to open up the
conversation around what like
from talking just about regenerative
culture with reading with a kind of
internal focus of how do we build the XR
movement and the climate response
movement to going we need to take this
energy and transform it into being the
regeneration rising and do our deep
adaptation work in place which will have
the dual function of preparing us to be
able to withstand collapse in economic
social and ecological systems that we
are in better because we've built local
resilience and we built the capacity to
collaborate and we built like we've done
the positive deep adaptation but at the
same time these actions could actually
if done well at a global scale
everywhere with diverse regenerative
cultures in place doing it proudly
expressing a difference to how somebody
else do that does it somewhere else
because it's that place talking and
being expressed then we're actually
building a system that might take us
through the eye of the needle and build
the world that takes us away from
extinction and creates collaborative
abundance and creates that evolutionary
leap where humanity moves from being
exploitative and degenerative to
becoming a healing and regenerative
influence on the ecosystems the bio
regions we we live in and ultimately
through doing this by scaling out doing
it community by community by a region by
by origin in the diversity of cultures
plura that's how we heal ourselves and
we heal the planet rather than creating
this is the answer and now we need to
put it out to our networks all over the
globe that would be a really big mistake